

Profile

I am FrontEnd Developer, focused on UI & Interaction Design, with 4+ years in Web Design, Web Development and entrepreneurial projects.

I'm interested in Web Applications Design, FrontEnd Development and User Experience, I have been involved in different projects with people around the world

Experience

Teacher @ DesafioLatam

05/2016 - Present

Creating new strategies for teaching of FrontEnd Technologies. Layouting Process. Teaching How to build Websites with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript/Angular for interaction.

Teacher @ Digital Arts University

05/2015 - Present

Teaching Swift [iOS] and Programming Basics. UX/UI Process. . Software Engineering. Mobile Development.

FrontEnd Engineer@ Paradoja

05/2015 - 10/2016

Coordinating and creating new strategies for detect and solving problems. Lead FrontEnd Web Development. UX/UI Process. Layout Websites.

FrontEnd Developer@ IndieStudio

10/2014 - 02/2015

Coordinating and creating Websites with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript for interaction. Used SMACSS Architecture, Preprocessors and Task. Runner for Automating Process. PageSpeed Performance.UX Process.

Web Designer & Software Developer @ Pueblo Bonito Consultores 06/2013 - 08/2013

Wrote maintainable and extensible code for a Desktop Application. Redesigned and Updated a Intranet and applied crossbrowser with IE7+.

FrontEnd Developer@ Freelance

06/2012 - Present

Implemented designs and layouting Web Apps and Web Sites. Wrote maintainable and extensible code and markup, using SMACSS Architecture.

Education

Engineering in Computers Systems

2008 - 2013

Technological Institute of La Paz

Psychology

2016 - Present

UTEG Zapopan

Details

Age: 27

Availability to travel: Yes

Passport: Yes

+5216121539704

me@omarsainz.com

www.omarsainz.com

Languages

Spanish

English

Passions

FrontEnd Development

Psychology

User Interface Design

Tools

FrontEnd

Design: CSS 3.

Frameworks: Bootstrap,

Materialize, UIKit.

Preprocessors: Stylus,

Sass.

Layout: HTML5.

Preprocessors: Jade

BackEnd & Programming

JavaScript/jQuery/Angular.

Python/Django.

Ruby/Ruby on Rails.

Editor: Sublime Text 3, VIM.

SCM: Git (GitHub & BitBucket).

Software: Adobe Photoshop,

Mockflow (Wireframes).

Mockups, UXPin, InVision.

Task Runner: Gulp. Webpack

Database: MySQL.

Methods

Kanban

Scrum

Volunteering

EP Manager [oGC]

02/2016 - 11/2016

AIESEC México